<p><?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?></p>
<text>
  <Title>THE OPEN WINDOW</Title>
  <p>  <dialogue>"My aunt will be down presently, <character name="Framton Nuttle">Mr. Nuttel</character>,"</dialogue> said a very self-possessed young lady of fifteen; <dialogue>"in the meantime you must try and put up with me."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton Nuttel</character> endeavoured to say the correct something which should duly flatter the niece of the moment without unduly discounting the aunt that was to come.  Privately he doubted more than ever whether these formal visits on a succession of total strangers would do much towards helping the nerve cure which he was supposed to be undergoing.</p></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I know how it will be,"</dialogue> his sister had said when he was preparing to migrate to this rural retreat; <dialogue>"you will bury yourself down there and not speak to a living soul, and your nerves will be worse than ever from moping.  I shall just give you letters of introduction to all the people I know there.  Some of them, as far as I can remember, were quite nice."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character> wondered whether <character name="Mrs. Sappleton">Mrs. Sappleton</character>, the lady to whom he was presenting one of the letters of introduction, came into the nice division.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Do you know many of the people round here?"</dialogue> asked the niece, when she judged that they had had sufficient silent communion.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Hardly a soul,"</dialogue> said <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character>.  <dialogue>"My sister was staying here, at the rectory, you know, some four years ago, and she gave me letters of introduction to some of the people here."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  He made the last statement in a tone of distinct regret.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Then you know practically nothing about my aunt?"</dialogue> pursued the self-possessed young lady.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Only her name and address,"</dialogue> admitted the caller.  He was wondering whether <character name="Mrs. Sappleton">Mrs. Sappleton</character> was in the married or widowed state.  An undefinable something about the room seemed to suggest masculine habitation.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Her great tragedy happened just three years ago,"</dialogue> said the child; <dialogue>"that would be since your sister’s time."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Her tragedy?"</dialogue> asked <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character>; somehow in this restful country spot tragedies seemed out of place.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"You may wonder why we keep that window wide open on an October afternoon,"</dialogue> said the niece, indicating a large French window that opened on to a lawn.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It is quite warm for the time of the year,"</dialogue> said <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character>; <dialogue>"but has that window got anything to do with the tragedy?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Out through that window, three years ago to a day, her husband and her two young brothers went off for their day’s shooting.  They never came back.  In crossing the moor to their favourite snipe-shooting ground they were all three engulfed in a treacherous piece of bog.  It had been that dreadful wet summer, you know, and places that were safe in other years gave way suddenly without warning.  Their bodies were never recovered.  That was the dreadful part of it."</dialogue>  Here the child’s voice lost its self-possessed note and became falteringly human.  <dialogue>"Poor aunt always thinks that they will come back some day, they and the little brown spaniel that was lost with them, and walk in at that window just as they used to do.  That is why the window is kept open every evening till it is quite dusk.  Poor dear aunt, she has often told me how they went out, her husband with his white waterproof coat over his arm, and <character name="Ronnie">Ronnie</character>, her youngest brother, singing ‘<character name="Bertie">Bertie</character>, why do you bound?’ as he always did to tease her, because she said it got on her nerves.  Do you know, sometimes on still, quiet evenings like this, I almost get a creepy feeling that they will all walk in through that window—"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  She broke off with a little shudder.  It was a relief to <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character> when the aunt bustled into the room with a whirl of apologies for being late in making her appearance.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I hope <character name="Vera">Vera</character> has been amusing you?"</dialogue> she said.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"She has been very interesting,"</dialogue> said <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I hope you don’t mind the open window,"</dialogue> said <character name="Mrs. Sappleton">Mrs. Sappleton</character> briskly; <dialogue>"my husband and brothers will be home directly from shooting, and they always come in this way.  They’ve been out for snipe in the marshes to-day, so they’ll make a fine mess over my poor carpets.  So like you men-folk, isn’t it?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  She rattled on cheerfully about the shooting and the scarcity of birds, and the prospects for duck in the winter.  To <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character> it was all purely horrible.  He made a desperate but only partially successful effort to turn the talk on to a less ghastly topic; he was conscious that his hostess was giving him only a fragment of her attention, and her eyes were constantly straying past him to the open window and the lawn beyond.  It was certainly an unfortunate coincidence that he should have paid his visit on this tragic anniversary.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The doctors agree in ordering me complete rest, an absence of mental excitement, and avoidance of anything in the nature of violent physical exercise,"</dialogue> announced <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character>, who laboured under the tolerably widespread delusion that total strangers and chance acquaintances are hungry for the least detail of one’s ailments and infirmities, their cause and cure.  <dialogue>"On the matter of diet they are not so much in agreement,"</dialogue> he continued.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"No?"</dialogue> said <character name="Mrs. Sappleton">Mrs. Sappleton</character>, in a voice which only replaced a yawn at the last moment.  Then she suddenly brightened into alert attention—but not to what <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character> was saying.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Here they are at last!"</dialogue> she cried.  <dialogue>"Just in time for tea, and don’t they look as if they were muddy up to the eyes!"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character> shivered slightly and turned towards the niece with a look intended to convey sympathetic comprehension.  The child was staring out through the open window with dazed horror in her eyes.  In a chill shock of nameless fear <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character> swung round in his seat and looked in the same direction.</p>

  <p>  In the deepening twilight three figures were walking across the lawn towards the window; they all carried guns under their arms, and one of them was additionally burdened with a white coat hung over his shoulders.  A tired brown spaniel kept close at their heels.  Noiselessly they neared the house, and then a hoarse young voice chanted out of the dusk: <dialogue>"I said, Bertie, why do you bound?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Framton Nuttle">Framton</character> grabbed wildly at his stick and hat; the hall-door, the gravel-drive, and the front gate were dimly-noted stages in his headlong retreat.  A cyclist coming along the road had to run into the hedge to avoid an imminent collision.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Here we are, my dear,"</dialogue> said the bearer of the white mackintosh, coming in through the window; <dialogue>"fairly muddy, but most of it’s dry.  Who was that who bolted out as we came up?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"A most extraordinary man, a <character name="Framton Nuttle">Mr. Nuttel</character>,"</dialogue> said <character name="Mrs. Sappleton">Mrs. Sappleton</character>; <dialogue>"could only talk about his illnesses, and dashed off without a word of good-bye or apology when you arrived.  One would think he had seen a ghost."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I expect it was the spaniel,"</dialogue> said the niece calmly; <dialogue>"he told me he had a horror of dogs.  He was once hunted into a cemetery somewhere on the banks of the <landform type="river">Ganges by a pack of pariah dogs, and had to spend the night in a newly dug grave with the creatures snarling and grinning and foaming just above him.  Enough to make anyone lose their nerve."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  Romance at short notice was her speciality.</p>

  <title>THE TREASURE SHIP</title>

  <p>  The great <vehicle type="ship">galleon lay in semi-retirement under the sand and weed and water of the northern bay where the fortune of war and weather had long ago ensconced it.  Three and a quarter centuries had passed since the day when it had taken the high seas as an important unit of a fighting squadron—precisely which squadron the learned were not agreed.  The <vehicle type="ship">galleon had brought nothing into the world, but it had, according to tradition and report, taken much out of it.  But how much?  There again the learned were in disagreement.  Some were as generous in their estimate as an income-tax assessor, others applied a species of higher criticism to the submerged treasure chests, and debased their contents to the currency of goblin gold.  Of the former school was <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character>, Duchess of Dulverton.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Lulu">The Duchess</character> was not only a believer in the existence of a sunken treasure of alluring proportions; she also believed that she knew of a method by which the said treasure might be precisely located and cheaply disembedded.  An aunt on her mother’s side of the family had been Maid of Honour at the <location type="court of law">Court of Monaco, and had taken a respectful interest in the deep-sea researches in which the Throne of that country, impatient perhaps of its terrestrial restrictions, was wont to immerse itself.  It was through the instrumentality of this relative that <character name="Lulu">the Duchess</character> learned of an invention, perfected and very nearly patented by a Monegaskan savant, by means of which the home-life of the Mediterranean sardine might be studied at a depth of many fathoms in a cold white light of more than ball-room brilliancy.  Implicated in this invention (and, in <character name="Lulu">the Duchess</character>’s eyes, the most attractive part of it) was an electric suction dredge, specially designed for dragging to the surface such objects of interest and value as might be found in the more accessible levels of the ocean-bed.  The rights of the invention were to be acquired for a matter of eighteen hundred francs, and the apparatus for a few thousand more.  <character name="Lulu">The Duchess</character> of Dulverton was rich, as the world counted wealth; she nursed the hope, of being one day rich at her own computation.  Companies had been formed and efforts had been made again and again during the course of three centuries to probe for the alleged treasures of the interesting <vehicle type="ship">galleon; with the aid of this invention she considered that she might go to work on the wreck privately and independently.  After all, one of her ancestors on her mother’s side was descended from Medina Sidonia, so she was of opinion that she had as much right to the treasure as anyone.  She acquired the invention and bought the apparatus.</p>

  <p>  Among other family ties and encumbrances, <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character> possessed a nephew, <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco Honiton</character>, a young gentleman who was blessed with a small income and a large circle of relatives, and lived impartially and precariously on both.  The name <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character> had been given him possibly in the hope that he might live up to its adventurous tradition, but he limited himself strictly to the home industry of adventurer, preferring to exploit the assured rather than to explore the unknown.  <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character>’s intercourse with him had been restricted of recent years to the negative processes of being out of town when he called on her, and short of money when he wrote to her.  Now, however, she bethought herself of his eminent suitability for the direction of a treasure-seeking experiment; if anyone could extract gold from an unpromising situation it would certainly be <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character>—of course, under the necessary safeguards in the way of supervision.  Where money was in question <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character>’s conscience was liable to fits of obstinate silence.</p>

  <p>  Somewhere on the west coast of Ireland the Dulverton property included a few acres of shingle, rock, and heather, too barren to support even an agrarian outrage, but embracing a small and fairly deep bay where the lobster yield was good in most seasons.  There was a bleak little house on the property, and for those who liked lobsters and solitude, and were able to accept an Irish cook’s ideas as to what might be perpetrated in the name of mayonnaise, Innisgluther was a tolerable exile during the summer months.  <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character> seldom went there herself, but she lent the house lavishly to friends and relations.  She put it now at <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character>’s disposal.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It will be the very place to practise and experiment with the salvage apparatus,"</dialogue> she said; <dialogue>"the bay is quite deep in places, and you will be able to test everything thoroughly before starting on the treasure hunt."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  In less than three weeks <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character> turned up in town to report progress.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The apparatus works beautifully,"</dialogue> he informed his aunt; <dialogue>"the deeper one got the clearer everything grew.  We found something in the way of a sunken wreck to operate on, too!"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"A wreck in Innisgluther Bay!"</dialogue> exclaimed <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"A submerged motor-boat, the Sub-Rosa,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"No! really?"</dialogue> said <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character>; <dialogue>"poor Billy Yuttley’s boat.  I remember it went down somewhere off that coast some three years ago.  His body was washed ashore at the Point.  People said at the time that the boat was capsized intentionally—a case of suicide, you know.  People always say that sort of thing when anything tragic happens."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"In this case they were right,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"What do you mean?"</dialogue> asked <character name="Lulu">the Duchess</character> hurriedly.  <dialogue>"What makes you think so?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I know,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character> simply.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Know?  How can you know?  How can anyone know?  The thing happened three years ago."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"In a locker of the Sub-Rosa I found a water-tight strong-box.  It contained papers."</dialogue>  <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character> paused with dramatic effect and searched for a moment in the inner breast-pocket of his coat.  He drew out a folded slip of paper.  <character name="Lulu">The Duchess</character> snatched at it in almost indecent haste and moved appreciably nearer the fireplace.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Was this in the Sub-Rosa’s strong-box?"</dialogue> she asked.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Oh no,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character> carelessly, <dialogue>"that is a list of the well-known people who would be involved in a very disagreeable scandal if the Sub-Rosa’s papers were made public.  I’ve put you at the head of it, otherwise it follows alphabetical order."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Lulu">The Duchess</character> gazed helplessly at the string of names, which seemed for the moment to include nearly every one she knew.  As a matter of fact, her own name at the head of the list exercised an almost paralysing effect on her thinking faculties.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Of course you have destroyed the papers?"</dialogue> she asked, when she had somewhat recovered herself.  She was conscious that she made the remark with an entire lack of conviction.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character> shook his head.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But you should have,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character> angrily; <dialogue>"if, as you say, they are highly compromising—"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Oh, they are, I assure you of that,"</dialogue> interposed the young man.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Then you should put them out of harm’s way at once.  Supposing anything should leak out, think of all these poor, unfortunate people who would be involved in the disclosures,"</dialogue> and <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character> tapped the list with an agitated gesture.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Unfortunate, perhaps, but not poor,"</dialogue> corrected <character name="Vasco Honiton">Vasco</character>; <dialogue>"if you read the list carefully you’ll notice that I haven’t troubled to include anyone whose financial standing isn’t above question."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character> glared at her nephew for some moments in silence.  Then she asked hoarsely: <dialogue>"What are you going to do?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Nothing—for the remainder of my life,"</dialogue> he answered meaningly.  <dialogue>"A little hunting, perhaps,"</dialogue> he continued, <dialogue>"and I shall have a villa at Florence.  The Villa Sub-Rosa would sound rather quaint and picturesque, don’t you think, and quite a lot of people would be able to attach a meaning to the name.  And I suppose I must have a hobby; I shall probably collect Raeburns."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Lulu">Lulu</character>’s relative, who lived at the Court of Monaco, got quite a snappish answer when she wrote recommending some further invention in the realm of marine research.</p>

  <title>THE COBWEB</title>
  <p>  The farmhouse kitchen probably stood where it did as a matter of accident or haphazard choice; yet its situation might have been planned by a master-strategist in farmhouse architecture.  Dairy and poultry-yard, and herb garden, and all the busy places of the farm seemed to lead by easy access into its wide flagged haven, where there was room for everything and where muddy boots left traces that were easily swept away.  And yet, for all that it stood so well in the centre of human bustle, its long, latticed window, with the wide window-seat, built into an embrasure beyond the huge fireplace, looked out on a wild spreading view of hill and heather and wooded combe.  The window nook made almost a little room in itself, quite the pleasantest room in the farm as far as situation and capabilities went.  Young <character name="Emma Ladbruk">Mrs. Ladbruk</character>, whose husband had just come into the farm by way of inheritance, cast covetous eyes on this snug corner, and her fingers itched to make it bright and cosy with chintz curtains and bowls of flowers, and a shelf or two of old china.  The musty farm parlour, looking out on to a prim, cheerless garden imprisoned within high, blank walls, was not a room that lent itself readily either to comfort or decoration.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"When we are more settled I shall work wonders in the way of making the kitchen habitable,"</dialogue> said the young woman to her occasional visitors.  There was an unspoken wish in those words, a wish which was unconfessed as well as unspoken.  <character name="Emma Ladbruk">Emma Ladbruk</character> was the mistress of the farm; jointly with her husband she might have her say, and to a certain extent her way, in ordering its affairs.  But she was not mistress of the kitchen.</p>

  <p>  On one of the shelves of an old dresser, in company with chipped sauce-boats, pewter jugs, cheese-graters, and paid bills, rested a worn and ragged Bible, on whose front page was the record, in faded ink, of a baptism dated ninety-four years ago.  <"<character name="Martha Crale">Martha Crale</character>" was the name written on that yellow page.  The yellow, wrinkled old dame who hobbled and muttered about the kitchen, looking like a dead autumn leaf which the winter winds still pushed hither and thither, had once been <character name="Martha Crale">Martha Crale</character>; for seventy odd years she had been <character name="Martha Crale">Martha Mountjoy</character>.  For longer than anyone could remember she had pattered to and fro between oven and wash-house and dairy, and out to chicken-run and garden, grumbling and muttering and scolding, but working unceasingly.  <character name="Emma Ladbruk">Emma Ladbruk</character>, of whose coming she took as little notice as she would of a bee wandering in at a window on a summer’s day, used at first to watch her with a kind of frightened curiosity.  She was so old and so much a part of the place, it was difficult to think of her exactly as a living thing.  Old Shep, the white-nozzled, stiff-limbed collie, waiting for his time to die, seemed almost more human than the withered, dried-up old woman.  He had been a riotous, roystering puppy, mad with the joy of life, when she was already a tottering, hobbling dame; now he was just a blind, breathing carcase, nothing more, and she still worked with frail energy, still swept and baked and washed, fetched and carried.  If there were something in these wise old dogs that did not perish utterly with death, Emma used to think to herself, what generations of ghost-dogs there must be out on those hills, that <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> had reared and fed and tended and spoken a last good-bye word to in that old kitchen.  And what memories she must have of human generations that had passed away in her time.  It was difficult for anyone, let alone a stranger like Emma, to get her to talk of the days that had been; her shrill, quavering speech was of doors that had been left unfastened, pails that had got mislaid, calves whose feeding-time was overdue, and the various little faults and lapses that chequer a farmhouse routine.  Now and again, when election time came round, she would unstore her recollections of the old names round which the fight had waged in the days gone by.  There had been a Palmerston, that had been a name down Tiverton way; Tiverton was not a far journey as the crow flies, but to <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> it was almost a foreign country.  Later there had been Northcotes and Aclands, and many other newer names that she had forgotten; the names changed, but it was always Libruls and Toories, Yellows and Blues.  And they always quarrelled and shouted as to who was right and who was wrong.  The one they quarrelled about most was a fine old gentleman with an angry face—she had seen his picture on the walls.  She had seen it on the floor too, with a rotten apple squashed over it, for the farm had changed its politics from time to time. <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> had never been on one side or the other; none of <dialogue>"they"</dialogue> had ever done the farm a stroke of good.  Such was her sweeping verdict, given with all a peasant’s distrust of the outside world.</p>

  <p>  When the half-frightened curiosity had somewhat faded away, <character name="Emma Ladbruk">Emma Ladbruk</character> was uncomfortably conscious of another feeling towards the old woman.  She was a quaint old tradition, lingering about the place, she was part and parcel of the farm itself, she was something at once pathetic and picturesque—but she was dreadfully in the way.  <character name="Emma Lardbruk">Emma</character> had come to the farm full of plans for little reforms and improvements, in part the result of training in the newest ways and methods, in part the outcome of her own ideas and fancies.  Reforms in the kitchen region, if those deaf old ears could have been induced to give them even a hearing, would have met with short shrift and scornful rejection, and the kitchen region spread over the zone of dairy and market business and half the work of the household.  <character name="Emma Lardbruk">Emma</character>, with the latest science of dead-poultry dressing at her finger-tips, sat by, an unheeded watcher, while old <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> trussed the chickens for the market-stall as she had trussed them for nearly fourscore years—all leg and no breast.  And the hundred hints anent effective cleaning and labour-lightening and the things that make for wholesomeness which the young woman was ready to impart or to put into action dropped away into nothingness before that wan, muttering, unheeding presence.  Above all, the coveted window corner, that was to be a dainty, cheerful oasis in the gaunt old kitchen, stood now choked and lumbered with a litter of odds and ends that <character name="Emma Lardbruk">Emma</character>, for all her nominal authority, would not have dared or cared to displace; over them seemed to be spun the protection of something that was like a human cobweb.  Decidedly <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> was in the way.  It would have been an unworthy meanness to have wished to see the span of that brave old life shortened by a few paltry months, but as the days sped by <character name="Emma Lardbruk">Emma</character> was conscious that the wish was there, disowned though it might be, lurking at the back of her mind.</p>

  <p>  She felt the meanness of the wish come over her with a qualm of self-reproach one day when she came into the kitchen and found an unaccustomed state of things in that usually busy quarter.  Old <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> was not working.  A basket of corn was on the floor by her side, and out in the yard the poultry were beginning to clamour a protest of overdue feeding-time.  But <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> sat huddled in a shrunken bunch on the window seat, looking out with her dim old eyes as though she saw something stranger than the autumn landscape.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Is anything the matter, <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character>?"</dialogue> asked the young woman.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"’Tis death, ’tis death a-coming,"</dialogue> answered the quavering voice; <dialogue>"I knew ’twere coming.  I knew it.  ’Tweren’t for nothing that old Shep’s been howling all morning.  An’ last night I heard the screech-owl give the death-cry, and there were something white as run across the yard yesterday; ’tweren’t a cat nor a stoat, ’twere something.  The fowls knew ’twere something; they all drew off to one side.  Ay, there’s been warnings.  I knew it were a-coming."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The young woman’s eyes clouded with pity.  The old thing sitting there so white and shrunken had once been a merry, noisy child, playing about in lanes and hay-lofts and farmhouse garrets; that had been eighty odd years ago, and now she was just a frail old body cowering under the approaching chill of the death that was coming at last to take her.  It was not probable that much could be done for her, but <character name="Emma Lardbruk">Emma</character> hastened away to get assistance and counsel.  Her husband, she knew, was down at a tree-felling some little distance off, but she might find some other intelligent soul who knew the old woman better than she did.  The farm, she soon found out, had that faculty common to farmyards of swallowing up and losing its human population.  The poultry followed her in interested fashion, and swine grunted interrogations at her from behind the bars of their styes, but barnyard and rickyard, orchard and stables and dairy, gave no reward to her search.  Then, as she retraced her steps towards the kitchen, she came suddenly on her cousin, young Mr. Jim, as every one called him, who divided his time between amateur horse-dealing, rabbit-shooting, and flirting with the farm maids.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I’m afraid old <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> is dying,"</dialogue> said <character name="Emma Lardbruk">Emma</character>.  Jim was not the sort of person to whom one had to break news gently.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Nonsense,"</dialogue> he said; <dialogue>"<character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> means to live to a hundred.  She told me so, and she’ll do it."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"She may be actually dying at this moment, or it may just be the beginning of the break-up,"</dialogue> persisted <character name="Emma Lardbruk">Emma</character>, with a feeling of contempt for the slowness and dulness of the young man.</p>

  <p>  A grin spread over his good-natured features.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It don’t look like it,"</dialogue> he said, nodding towards the yard.  <character name="Emma Lardbruk">Emma</character> turned to catch the meaning of his remark.  Old <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> stood in the middle of a mob of poultry scattering handfuls of grain around her.  The turkey-cock, with the bronzed sheen of his feathers and the purple-red of his wattles, the gamecock, with the glowing metallic lustre of his Eastern plumage, the hens, with their ochres and buffs and umbers and their scarlet combs, and the drakes, with their bottle-green heads, made a medley of rich colour, in the centre of which the old woman looked like a withered stalk standing amid a riotous growth of gaily-hued flowers.  But she threw the grain deftly amid the wilderness of beaks, and her quavering voice carried as far as the two people who were watching her.  She was still harping on the theme of death coming to the farm.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I knew ’twere a-coming.  There’s been signs an’ warnings."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Who’s dead, then, old Mother?"</dialogue> called out the young man.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"’Tis young Mister Ladbruk,"</dialogue> she shrilled back; <dialogue>"they’ve just a-carried his body in.  Run out of the way of a tree that was coming down an’ ran hisself on to an iron post.  Dead when they picked un up.  Aye, I knew ’twere coming."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  And she turned to fling a handful of barley at a belated group of guinea-fowl that came racing toward her.</p>

   * * * * *

  <p>  The farm was a family property, and passed to the rabbit-shooting cousin as the next-of-kin.  <character name="Emma Ladbruk">Emma Ladbruk</character> drifted out of its history as a bee that had wandered in at an open window might flit its way out again.  On a cold grey morning she stood waiting, with her boxes already stowed in the farm cart, till the last of the market produce should be ready, for the train she was to catch was of less importance than the chickens and butter and eggs that were to be offered for sale.  From where she stood she could see an angle of the long latticed window that was to have been cosy with curtains and gay with bowls of flowers.  Into her mind came the thought that for months, perhaps for years, long after she had been utterly forgotten, a white, unheeding face would be seen peering out through those latticed panes, and a weak muttering voice would be heard quavering up and down those flagged passages.  She made her way to a narrow barred casement that opened into the farm larder.  Old <character name="Martha Crale">Martha</character> was standing at a table trussing a pair of chickens for the market stall as she had trussed them for nearly fourscore years.</p>

  <title>THE LULL</title>
  <p>  <dialogue>"I’ve asked <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer Springfield</character> to spend Sunday with us and stop the night,"</dialogue> announced Mrs. Durmot at the breakfast-table.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I thought he was in the throes of an election,"</dialogue> remarked her husband.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Exactly; the poll is on Wednesday, and the poor man will have worked himself to a shadow by that time.  Imagine what electioneering must be like in this awful soaking rain, going along slushy country roads and speaking to damp audiences in draughty schoolrooms, day after day for a fortnight.  He’ll have to put in an appearance at some place of worship on Sunday morning, and he can come to us immediately afterwards and have a thorough respite from everything connected with politics.  I won’t let him even think of them.  I’ve had the picture of Cromwell dissolving the Long Parliament taken down from the staircase, and even the portrait of Lord Rosebery’s ‘Ladas’ removed from the smoking-room.  And <character name="Vera">Vera</character>,"</dialogue> added Mrs. Durmot, turning to her sixteen-year-old niece, <dialogue>"be careful what colour ribbon you wear in your hair; not blue or yellow on any account; those are the rival party colours, and emerald green or orange would be almost as bad, with this Home Rule business to the fore."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"On state occasions I always wear a black ribbon in my hair,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character> with crushing dignity.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer Springfield</character> was a rather cheerless, oldish young man, who went into politics somewhat in the spirit in which other people might go into half-mourning.  Without being an enthusiast, however, he was a fairly strenuous plodder, and Mrs. Durmot had been reasonably near the mark in asserting that he was working at high pressure over this election.  The restful lull which his hostess enforced on him was decidedly welcome, and yet the nervous excitement of the contest had too great a hold on him to be totally banished.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I know he’s going to sit up half the night working up points for his final speeches,"</dialogue> said Mrs. Durmot regretfully; <dialogue>"however, we’ve kept politics at arm’s length all the afternoon and evening.  More than that we cannot do."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"That remains to be seen,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character>, but she said it to herself.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> had scarcely shut his bedroom door before he was immersed in a sheaf of notes and pamphlets, while a fountain-pen and pocket-book were brought into play for the due marshalling of useful facts and discreet fictions.  He had been at work for perhaps thirty-five minutes, and the house was seemingly consecrated to the healthy slumber of country life, when a stifled squealing and scuffling in the passage was followed by a loud tap at his door.  Before he had time to answer, a much-encumbered <character name="Vera">Vera</character> burst into the room with the question; <dialogue>"I say, can I leave these here?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"These"</dialogue> were a small black pig and a lusty specimen of black-red gamecock.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> was moderately fond of animals, and particularly interested in small livestock rearing from the economic point of view; in fact, one of the pamphlets on which he was at that moment engaged warmly advocated the further development of the pig and poultry industry in our rural districts; but he was pardonably unwilling to share even a commodious bedroom with samples of henroost and stye products.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Wouldn’t they be happier somewhere outside?"</dialogue> he asked, tactfully expressing his own preference in the matter in an apparent solicitude for theirs.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"There is no outside,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character> impressively, <dialogue>"nothing but a waste of dark, swirling waters.  The reservoir at Brinkley has burst."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I didn’t know there was a reservoir at Brinkley,"</dialogue> said <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Well, there isn’t now, it’s jolly well all over the place, and as we stand particularly low we’re the centre of an inland sea just at present.  You see the river has overflowed its banks as well."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Good gracious!  Have any lives been lost?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Heaps, I should say.  The second housemaid has already identified three bodies that have floated past the billiard-room window as being the young man she’s engaged to.  Either she’s engaged to a large assortment of the population round here or else she’s very careless at identification.  Of course it may be the same body coming round again and again in a swirl; I hadn’t thought of that."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But we ought to go out and do rescue work, oughtn’t we?"</dialogue> said <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character>, with the instinct of a Parliamentary candidate for getting into the local limelight.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"We can’t,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character> decidedly, <dialogue>"we haven’t any boats and we’re cut off by a raging torrent from any human habitation.  My aunt particularly hoped you would keep to your room and not add to the confusion, but she thought it would be so kind of you if you would take in Hartlepool’s Wonder, the gamecock, you know, for the night.  You see, there are eight other gamecocks, and they fight like furies if they get together, so we’re putting one in each bedroom.  The fowl-houses are all flooded out, you know.  And then I thought perhaps you wouldn’t mind taking in this wee piggie; he’s rather a little love, but he has a vile temper.  He gets that from his mother—not that I like to say things against her when she’s lying dead and drowned in her stye, poor thing.  What he really wants is a man’s firm hand to keep him in order.  I’d try and grapple with him myself, only I’ve got my chow in my room, you know, and he goes for pigs wherever he finds them."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Couldn’t the pig go in the bathroom?"</dialogue> asked <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> faintly, wishing that he had taken up as determined a stand on the subject of bedroom swine as the chow had.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The bathroom?"</dialogue> <character name="Vera">Vera</character> laughed shrilly.  <dialogue>"It’ll be full of Boy Scouts till morning if the hot water holds out."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Boy Scouts?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Yes, thirty of them came to rescue us while the water was only waist-high; then it rose another three feet or so and we had to rescue them.  We’re giving them hot baths in batches and drying their clothes in the hot-air cupboard, but, of course, drenched clothes don’t dry in a minute, and the corridor and staircase are beginning to look like a bit of coast scenery by Tuke.  Two of the boys are wearing your Melton overcoat; I hope you don’t mind."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s a new overcoat,"</dialogue> said <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character>, with every indication of minding dreadfully.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"You’ll take every care of Hartlepool’s Wonder, won’t you?"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character>.  <dialogue>"His mother took three firsts at Birmingham, and he was second in the cockerel class last year at Gloucester.  He’ll probably roost on the rail at the bottom of your bed.  I wonder if he’d feel more at home if some of his wives were up here with him?  The hens are all in the pantry, and I think I could pick out Hartlepool Helen; she’s his favourite."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> showed a belated firmness on the subject of Hartlepool Helen, and <character name="Vera">Vera</character> withdrew without pressing the point, having first settled the gamecock on his extemporised perch and taken an affectionate farewell of the pigling.  <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> undressed and got into bed with all due speed, judging that the pig would abate its inquisitorial restlessness once the light was turned out.  As a substitute for a cosy, straw-bedded sty the room offered, at first inspection, few attractions, but the disconsolate animal suddenly discovered an appliance in which the most luxuriously contrived piggeries were notably deficient.  The sharp edge of the underneath part of the bed was pitched at exactly the right elevation to permit the pigling to scrape himself ecstatically backwards and forwards, with an artistic humping of the back at the crucial moment and an accompanying gurgle of long-drawn delight.  The gamecock, who may have fancied that he was being rocked in the branches of a pine-tree, bore the motion with greater fortitude than <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> was able to command.  A series of slaps directed at the pig’s body were accepted more as an additional and pleasing irritant than as a criticism of conduct or a hint to desist; evidently something more than a man’s firm hand was needed to deal with the case.  <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> slipped out of bed in search of a weapon of dissuasion.  There was sufficient light in the room to enable the pig to detect this manœuvre, and the vile temper, inherited from the drowned mother, found full play.  <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> bounded back into bed, and his conqueror, after a few threatening snorts and champings of its jaws, resumed its massage operations with renewed zeal.  During the long wakeful hours which ensued <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> tried to distract his mind from his own immediate troubles by dwelling with decent sympathy on the second housemaid’s bereavement, but he found himself more often wondering how many Boy Scouts were sharing his Melton overcoat.  The rôle of Saint Martin malgré lui was not one which appealed to him.</p>

  <p>  Towards dawn the pigling fell into a happy slumber, and <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> might have followed its example, but at about the same time Stupor Hartlepooli gave a rousing crow, clattered down to the floor and forthwith commenced a spirited combat with his reflection in the wardrobe mirror.  Remembering that the bird was more or less under his care <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character> performed Hague Tribunal offices by draping a bath-towel over the provocative mirror, but the ensuing peace was local and short-lived.  The deflected energies of the gamecock found new outlet in a sudden and sustained attack on the sleeping and temporarily inoffensive pigling, and the duel which followed was desperate and embittered beyond any possibility of effective intervention.  The feathered combatant had the advantage of being able, when hard pressed, to take refuge on the bed, and freely availed himself of this circumstance; the pigling never quite succeeded in hurling himself on to the same eminence, but it was not from want of trying.</p>

  <p>  Neither side could claim any decisive success, and the struggle had been practically fought to a standstill by the time that the maid appeared with the early morning tea.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Lor, sir,"</dialogue> she exclaimed in undisguised astonishment, <dialogue>"do you want those animals in your room?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  Want!</p>

  <p>  The pigling, as though aware that it might have outstayed its welcome, dashed out at the door, and the gamecock followed it at a more dignified pace.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"If Miss <character name="Vera">Vera</character>’s dog sees that pig—!"</dialogue> exclaimed the maid, and hurried off to avert such a catastrophe.</p>

  <p>  A cold suspicion was stealing over <character name="Latimer Springfield">Latimer</character>’s mind; he went to the window and drew up the blind.  A light, drizzling rain was falling, but there was not the faintest trace of any inundation.</p>

  <p>  Some half-hour later he met <character name="Vera">Vera</character> on the way to the breakfast-room.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I should not like to think of you as a deliberate liar,"</dialogue> he observed coldly, <dialogue>"but one occasionally has to do things one does not like."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"At any rate I kept your mind from dwelling on politics all the night,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character>.</p>

  <p>  Which was, of course, perfectly true.</p>

  <title>THE UNKINDEST BLOW</title>
  <p>  The season of strikes seemed to have run itself to a standstill.  Almost every trade and industry and calling in which a dislocation could possibly be engineered had indulged in that luxury.  The last and least successful convulsion had been the strike of the World’s Union of Zoological Garden attendants, who, pending the settlement of certain demands, refused to minister further to the wants of the animals committed to their charge or to allow any other keepers to take their place.  In this case the threat of the Zoological Gardens authorities that if the men <dialogue>"came out"</dialogue> the animals should come out also had intensified and precipitated the crisis.  The imminent prospect of the larger carnivores, to say nothing of rhinoceroses and bull bison, roaming at large and unfed in the heart of London, was not one which permitted of prolonged conferences.  The Government of the day, which from its tendency to be a few hours behind the course of events had been nicknamed the Government of the afternoon, was obliged to intervene with promptitude and decision.  A strong force of Bluejackets was despatched to Regent’s Park to take over the temporarily abandoned duties of the strikers.  Bluejackets were chosen in preference to land forces, partly on account of the traditional readiness of the British Navy to go anywhere and do anything, partly by reason of the familiarity of the average sailor with monkeys, parrots, and other tropical fauna, but chiefly at the urgent request of the First Lord of the Admiralty, who was keenly desirous of an opportunity for performing some personal act of unobtrusive public service within the province of his department.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"If he insists on feeding the infant jaguar himself, in defiance of its mother’s wishes, there may be another by-election in the north,"</dialogue> said one of his colleagues, with a hopeful inflection in his voice.  <dialogue>"By-elections are not very desirable at present, but we must not be selfish."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  As a matter of fact the strike collapsed peacefully without any outside intervention.  The majority of the keepers had become so attached to their charges that they returned to work of their own accord.</p>

  <p>  And then the nation and the newspapers turned with a sense of relief to happier things.  It seemed as if a new era of contentment was about to dawn.  Everybody had struck who could possibly want to strike or who could possibly be cajoled or bullied into striking, whether they wanted to or not.  The lighter and brighter side of life might now claim some attention.  And conspicuous among the other topics that sprang into sudden prominence was the pending Falvertoon divorce suit.</p>

  <p>  <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">The Duke of Falvertoon</character> was one of those human hors d’œuvres that stimulate the public appetite for sensation without giving it much to feed on.  As a mere child he had been precociously brilliant; he had declined the editorship of the Anglian Review at an age when most boys are content to have declined mensa, a table, and though he could not claim to have originated the Futurist movement in literature, his <dialogue>"Letters to a possible Grandson,"</dialogue> written at the age of fourteen, had attracted considerable notice.  In later days his brilliancy had been less conspicuously displayed.  During a debate in the House of Lords on affairs in Morocco, at a moment when that country, for the fifth time in seven years, had brought half Europe to the verge of war, he had interpolated the remark <dialogue>"a little Moor and how much it is,"</dialogue> but in spite of the encouraging reception accorded to this one political utterance he was never tempted to a further display in that direction.  It began to be generally understood that he did not intend to supplement his numerous town and country residences by living overmuch in the public eye.</p>

  <p>  And then had come the unlooked-for tidings of the imminent proceedings for divorce.  And such a divorce!  There were cross-suits and allegations and counter-allegations, charges of cruelty and desertion, everything in fact that was necessary to make the case one of the most complicated and sensational of its kind.  And the number of distinguished people involved or cited as witnesses not only embraced both political parties in the realm and several Colonial governors, but included an exotic contingent from France, Hungary, the United States of North America, and the Grand Duchy of Baden.  Hotel accommodation of the more expensive sort began to experience a strain on its resources.  <dialogue>"It will be quite like the Durbar without the elephants,"</dialogue> exclaimed an enthusiastic lady who, to do her justice, had never seen a Durbar.  The general feeling was one of thankfulness that the last of the strikes had been got over before the date fixed for the hearing of the great suit.</p>

  <p>  As a reaction from the season of gloom and industrial strife that had just passed away the agencies that purvey and stage-manage sensations laid themselves out to do their level best on this momentous occasion.  Men who had made their reputations as special descriptive writers were mobilised from distant corners of Europe and the further side of the Atlantic in order to enrich with their pens the daily printed records of the case; one word-painter, who specialised in descriptions of how witnesses turn pale under cross-examination, was summoned hurriedly back from a famous and prolonged murder trial in Sicily, where indeed his talents were being decidedly wasted.  Thumb-nail artists and expert kodak manipulators were retained at extravagant salaries, and special dress reporters were in high demand.  An enterprising Paris firm of costume builders presented the defendant Duchess with three special creations, to be worn, marked, learned, and extensively reported at various critical stages of the trial; and as for the cinematograph agents, their industry and persistence was untiring.  Films representing the <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">Duke</character> saying good-bye to his favourite canary on the eve of the trial were in readiness weeks before the event was due to take place; other films depicted the Duchess holding imaginary consultations with fictitious lawyers or making a light repast off specially advertised vegetarian sandwiches during a supposed luncheon interval.  As far as human foresight and human enterprise could go nothing was lacking to make the trial a success.</p>

  <p>  Two days before the case was down for hearing the advance reporter of an important syndicate obtained an interview with the <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">Duke</character> for the purpose of gleaning some final grains of information concerning his Grace’s personal arrangements during the trial.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I suppose I may say this will be one of the biggest affairs of its kind during the lifetime of a generation,"</dialogue> began the reporter as an excuse for the unsparing minuteness of detail that he was about to make quest for.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I suppose so—if it comes off,"</dialogue> said the <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">Duke</character> lazily.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"If?"</dialogue> queried the reporter, in a voice that was something between a gasp and a scream.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The Duchess and I are both thinking of going on strike,"</dialogue> said the <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">Duke</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Strike!"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The baleful word flashed out in all its old hideous familiarity.  Was there to be no end to its recurrence?</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Do you mean,"</dialogue> faltered the reporter, <dialogue>"that you are contemplating a mutual withdrawal of the charges?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Precisely,"</dialogue> said the <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">Duke</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But think of the arrangements that have been made, the special reporting, the cinematographs, the catering for the distinguished foreign witnesses, the prepared music-hall allusions; think of all the money that has been sunk—"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Exactly,"</dialogue> said the <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">Duke</character> coldly, <dialogue>"the Duchess and I have realised that it is we who provide the material out of which this great far-reaching industry has been built up.  Widespread employment will be given and enormous profits made during the duration of the case, and we, on whom all the stress and racket falls, will get—what?  An unenviable notoriety and the privilege of paying heavy legal expenses whichever way the verdict goes.  Hence our decision to strike.  We don’t wish to be reconciled; we fully realise that it is a grave step to take, but unless we get some reasonable consideration out of this vast stream of wealth and industry that we have called into being we intend coming out of court and staying out.  Good afternoon."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The news of this latest strike spread universal dismay.  Its inaccessibility to the ordinary methods of persuasion made it peculiarly formidable.  If the <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">Duke</character> and Duchess persisted in being reconciled the Government could hardly be called on to interfere.  Public opinion in the shape of social ostracism might be brought to bear on them, but that was as far as coercive measures could go.  There was nothing for it but a conference, with powers to propose liberal terms.  As it was, several of the foreign witnesses had already departed and others had telegraphed cancelling their hotel arrangements.</p>

  <p>  The conference, protracted, uncomfortable, and occasionally acrimonious, succeeded at last in arranging for a resumption of litigation, but it was a fruitless victory.  The <character name="The Duke of Falvertoon">Duke</character>, with a touch of his earlier precocity, died of premature decay a fortnight before the date fixed for the new trial.</p>

  <title>THE ROMANCERS</title>
  <p>  It was autumn in London, that blessed season between the harshness of winter and the insincerities of summer; a trustful season when one buys bulbs and sees to the registration of one’s vote, believing perpetually in spring and a change of Government.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Morton Corsby">Morton Crosby</character> sat on a bench in a secluded corner of Hyde Park, lazily enjoying a cigarette and watching the slow grazing promenade of a pair of snow-geese, the male looking rather like an albino edition of the russet-hued female.  Out of the corner of his eye <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character> also noted with some interest the hesitating hoverings of a human figure, which had passed and repassed his seat two or three times at shortening intervals, like a wary crow about to alight near some possibly edible morsel.  Inevitably the figure came to an anchorage on the bench, within easy talking distance of its original occupant.  The uncared-for clothes, the aggressive, grizzled beard, and the furtive, evasive eye of the new-comer bespoke the professional cadger, the man who would undergo hours of humiliating tale-spinning and rebuff rather than adventure on half a day’s decent work.</p>

  <p>  For a while the new-comer fixed his eyes straight in front of him in a strenuous, unseeing gaze; then his voice broke out with the insinuating inflection of one who has a story to retail well worth any loiterer’s while to listen to.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s a strange world,"</dialogue> he said.</p>

  <p>  As the statement met with no response he altered it to the form of a question.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I daresay you’ve found it to be a strange world, mister?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"As far as I am concerned,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>, <dialogue>"the strangeness has worn off in the course of thirty-six years."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Ah,"</dialogue> said the greybeard, <dialogue>"I could tell you things that you’d hardly believe.  Marvellous things that have really happened to me."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Nowadays there is no demand for marvellous things that have really happened,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character> discouragingly; <dialogue>"the professional writers of fiction turn these things out so much better.  For instance, my neighbours tell me wonderful, incredible things that their Aberdeens and chows and borzois have done; I never listen to them.  On the other hand, I have read ‘The Hound of the Baskervilles’ three times."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The greybeard moved uneasily in his seat; then he opened up new country.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I take it that you are a professing Christian,"</dialogue> he observed.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I am a prominent and I think I may say an influential member of the Mussulman community of Eastern Persia,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>, making an excursion himself into the realms of fiction.</p>

  <p>  The greybeard was obviously disconcerted at this new check to introductory conversation, but the defeat was only momentary.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Persia.  I should never have taken you for a Persian,"</dialogue> he remarked, with a somewhat aggrieved air.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I am not,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>; <dialogue>"my father was an Afghan."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"An Afghan!"</dialogue> said the other, smitten into bewildered silence for a moment.  Then he recovered himself and renewed his attack.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Afghanistan.  Ah!  We’ve had some wars with that country; now, I daresay, instead of fighting it we might have learned something from it.  A very wealthy country, I believe.  No real poverty there."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  He raised his voice on the word <dialogue>"poverty"</dialogue> with a suggestion of intense feeling.  <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character> saw the opening and avoided it.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It possesses, nevertheless, a number of highly talented and ingenious beggars,"</dialogue> he said; <dialogue>"if I had not spoken so disparagingly of marvellous things that have really happened I would tell you the story of Ibrahim and the eleven camel-loads of blotting-paper.  Also I have forgotten exactly how it ended."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"My own life-story is a curious one,"</dialogue> said the stranger, apparently stifling all desire to hear the history of Ibrahim; <dialogue>"I was not always as you see me now."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"We are supposed to undergo complete change in the course of every seven years,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>, as an explanation of the foregoing announcement.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I mean I was not always in such distressing circumstances as I am at present,"</dialogue> pursued the stranger doggedly.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"That sounds rather rude,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character> stiffly, <dialogue>"considering that you are at present talking to a man reputed to be one of the most gifted conversationalists of the Afghan border."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I don’t mean in that way,"</dialogue> said the greybeard hastily; <dialogue>"I’ve been very much interested in your conversation.  I was alluding to my unfortunate financial situation.  You mayn’t hardly believe it, but at the present moment I am absolutely without a farthing.  Don’t see any prospect of getting any money, either, for the next few days.  I don’t suppose you’ve ever found yourself in such a position,"</dialogue> he added.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"In the town of Yom,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>, <dialogue>"which is in Southern Afghanistan, and which also happens to be my birthplace, there was a Chinese philosopher who used to say that one of the three chiefest human blessings was to be absolutely without money.  I forget what the other two were."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Ah, I daresay,"</dialogue> said the stranger, in a tone that betrayed no enthusiasm for the philosopher’s memory; <dialogue>"and did he practise what he preached?  That’s the test."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"He lived happily with very little money or resources,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Then I expect he had friends who would help him liberally whenever he was in difficulties, such as I am in at present."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"In Yom,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>, <dialogue>"it is not necessary to have friends in order to obtain help.  Any citizen of Yom would help a stranger as a matter of course."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The greybeard was now genuinely interested.</p>

  <p>  The conversation had at last taken a favourable turn.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"If someone, like me, for instance, who was in undeserved difficulties, asked a citizen of that town you speak of for a small loan to tide over a few days’ impecuniosity—five shillings, or perhaps a rather larger sum—would it be given to him as a matter of course?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"There would be a certain preliminary,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>; <dialogue>"one would take him to a wine-shop and treat him to a measure of wine, and then, after a little high-flown conversation, one would put the desired sum in his hand and wish him good-day.  It is a roundabout way of performing a simple transaction, but in the East all ways are roundabout."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The listener’s eyes were glittering.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Ah,"</dialogue> he exclaimed, with a thin sneer ringing meaningly through his words, <dialogue>"I suppose you’ve given up all those generous customs since you left your town.  Don’t practise them now, I expect."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"No one who has lived in Yom,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character> fervently, <dialogue>"and remembers its green hills covered with apricot and almond trees, and the cold water that rushes down like a caress from the upland snows and dashes under the little wooden bridges, no one who remembers these things and treasures the memory of them would ever give up a single one of its unwritten laws and customs.  To me they are as binding as though I still lived in that hallowed home of my youth."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Then if I was to ask you for a small loan—"</dialogue> began the greybeard fawningly, edging nearer on the seat and hurriedly wondering how large he might safely make his request, <dialogue>"if I was to ask you for, say—"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"At any other time, certainly,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character>; <dialogue>"in the months of November and December, however, it is absolutely forbidden for anyone of our race to give or receive loans or gifts; in fact, one does not willingly speak of them.  It is considered unlucky.  We will therefore close this discussion."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But it is still October!"</dialogue> exclaimed the adventurer with an eager, angry whine, as <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character> rose from his seat; <dialogue>"wants eight days to the end of the month!"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The Afghan November began yesterday,"</dialogue> said <character name="Morton Crosby">Crosby</character> severely, and in another moment he was striding across the Park, leaving his recent companion scowling and muttering furiously on the seat.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I don’t believe a word of his story,"</dialogue> he chattered to himself; <dialogue>"pack of nasty lies from beginning to end.  Wish I’d told him so to his face.  Calling himself an Afghan!"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The snorts and snarls that escaped from him for the next quarter of an hour went far to support the truth of the old saying that two of a trade never agree.</p>

  <title> THE SCHARTZ-METTERKLUME METHOD</title>
  <p>  <character name="Lady Carlotta">Lady Carlotta</character> stepped out on to the platform of the small wayside station and took a turn or two up and down its uninteresting length, to kill time till the train should be pleased to proceed on its way.  Then, in the roadway beyond, she saw a horse struggling with a more than ample load, and a carter of the sort that seems to bear a sullen hatred against the animal that helps him to earn a living.  <character name="Lady Carlotta">Lady Carlotta</character> promptly betook her to the roadway, and put rather a different complexion on the struggle.  Certain of her acquaintances were wont to give her plentiful admonition as to the undesirability of interfering on behalf of a distressed animal, such interference being <dialogue>"none of her business."</dialogue>  Only once had she put the doctrine of non-interference into practice, when one of its most eloquent exponents had been besieged for nearly three hours in a small and extremely uncomfortable may-tree by an angry boar-pig, while <character name="Lady Carlotta">Lady Carlotta</character>, on the other side of the fence, had proceeded with the water-colour sketch she was engaged on, and refused to interfere between the boar and his prisoner.  It is to be feared that she lost the friendship of the ultimately rescued lady.  On this occasion she merely lost the train, which gave way to the first sign of impatience it had shown throughout the journey, and steamed off without her.  She bore the desertion with philosophical indifference; her friends and relations were thoroughly well used to the fact of her luggage arriving without her.  She wired a vague non-committal message to her destination to say that she was coming on <dialogue>"by another train."</dialogue>  Before she had time to think what her next move might be she was confronted by an imposingly attired lady, who seemed to be taking a prolonged mental inventory of her clothes and looks.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"You must be <character name="Lady Carlotta">Miss Hope</character>, the governess I’ve come to meet,"</dialogue> said the apparition, in a tone that admitted of very little argument.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Very well, if I must I must,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Carlotta">Lady Carlotta</character> to herself with dangerous meekness.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I am <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character>,"</dialogue> continued the lady; <dialogue>"and where, pray, is your luggage?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s gone astray,"</dialogue> said the alleged governess, falling in with the excellent rule of life that the absent are always to blame; the luggage had, in point of fact, behaved with perfect correctitude.  <dialogue>"I’ve just telegraphed about it,"</dialogue> she added, with a nearer approach to truth.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"How provoking,"</dialogue> said <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character>; <dialogue>"these railway companies are so careless.  However, my maid can lend you things for the night,"</dialogue> and she led the way to her car.</p>

  <p>  During the drive to the Quabarl mansion <character name="Lady Carlotta">Lady Carlotta</character> was impressively introduced to the nature of the charge that had been thrust upon her; she learned that Claude and Wilfrid were delicate, sensitive young people, that Irene had the artistic temperament highly developed, and that Viola was something or other else of a mould equally commonplace among children of that class and type in the twentieth century.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I wish them not only to be taught,"</dialogue> said <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character>, <dialogue>"but interested in what they learn.  In their history lessons, for instance, you must try to make them feel that they are being introduced to the life-stories of men and women who really lived, not merely committing a mass of names and dates to memory.  French, of course, I shall expect you to talk at meal-times several days in the week."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I shall talk French four days of the week and Russian in the remaining three."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Russian?  My dear <character name="Lady Carlotta">Miss Hope</character>, no one in the house speaks or understands Russian."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"That will not embarrass me in the least,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Carlotta">Lady Carlotta</character> coldly.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character>, to use a colloquial expression, was knocked off her perch.  She was one of those imperfectly self-assured individuals who are magnificent and autocratic as long as they are not seriously opposed.  The least show of unexpected resistance goes a long way towards rendering them cowed and apologetic.  When the new governess failed to express wondering admiration of the large newly-purchased and expensive car, and lightly alluded to the superior advantages of one or two makes which had just been put on the market, the discomfiture of her patroness became almost abject.  Her feelings were those which might have animated a general of ancient warfaring days, on beholding his heaviest battle-elephant ignominiously driven off the field by slingers and javelin throwers.</p>

  <p>  At dinner that evening, although reinforced by her husband, who usually duplicated her opinions and lent her moral support generally, <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character> regained none of her lost ground.  The governess not only helped herself well and truly to wine, but held forth with considerable show of critical knowledge on various vintage matters, concerning which the Quabarls were in no wise able to pose as authorities.  Previous governesses had limited their conversation on the wine topic to a respectful and doubtless sincere expression of a preference for water.  When this one went as far as to recommend a wine firm in whose hands you could not go very far wrong <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character> thought it time to turn the conversation into more usual channels.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"We got very satisfactory references about you from Canon Teep,"</dialogue> she observed; <dialogue>"a very estimable man, I should think."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Drinks like a fish and beats his wife, otherwise a very lovable character,"</dialogue> said the governess imperturbably.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"My dear <character name="Lady Carlotta">Miss Hope</character>!  I trust you are exaggerating,"</dialogue> exclaimed the Quabarls in unison.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"One must in justice admit that there is some provocation,"</dialogue> continued the romancer.  <dialogue>"Mrs. Teep is quite the most irritating bridge-player that I have ever sat down with; her leads and declarations would condone a certain amount of brutality in her partner, but to souse her with the contents of the only soda-water syphon in the house on a Sunday afternoon, when one couldn’t get another, argues an indifference to the comfort of others which I cannot altogether overlook.  You may think me hasty in my judgments, but it was practically on account of the syphon incident that I left."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"We will talk of this some other time,"</dialogue> said <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character> hastily.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I shall never allude to it again,"</dialogue> said the governess with decision.</p>

  <p>  Mr. Quabarl made a welcome diversion by asking what studies the new instructress proposed to inaugurate on the morrow.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"History to begin with,"</dialogue> she informed him.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Ah, history,"</dialogue> he observed sagely; <dialogue>"now in teaching them history you must take care to interest them in what they learn.  You must make them feel that they are being introduced to the life-stories of men and women who really lived—"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I’ve told her all that,"</dialogue> interposed <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I teach history on the Schartz-Metterklume method,"</dialogue> said the governess loftily.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Ah, yes,"</dialogue> said her listeners, thinking it expedient to assume an acquaintance at least with the name.</p>

  <p>  * * * * *</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"What are you children doing out here?"</dialogue> demanded <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character> the next morning, on finding Irene sitting rather glumly at the head of the stairs, while her sister was perched in an attitude of depressed discomfort on the window-seat behind her, with a wolf-skin rug almost covering her.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"We are having a history lesson,"</dialogue> came the unexpected reply.  <dialogue>"I am supposed to be Rome, and Viola up there is the she-wolf; not a real wolf, but the figure of one that the Romans used to set store by—I forget why.  Claude and Wilfrid have gone to fetch the shabby women."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The shabby women?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Yes, they’ve got to carry them off.  They didn’t want to, but <character name="Lady Carlotta">Miss Hope</character> got one of father’s fives-bats and said she’d give them a number nine spanking if they didn’t, so they’ve gone to do it."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  A loud, angry screaming from the direction of the lawn drew <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character> thither in hot haste, fearful lest the threatened castigation might even now be in process of infliction.  The outcry, however, came principally from the two small daughters of the lodge-keeper, who were being hauled and pushed towards the house by the panting and dishevelled Claude and Wilfrid, whose task was rendered even more arduous by the incessant, if not very effectual, attacks of the captured maidens’ small brother.  The governess, fives-bat in hand, sat negligently on the stone balustrade, presiding over the scene with the cold impartiality of a Goddess of Battles.  A furious and repeated chorus of <dialogue>"I’ll tell muvver"</dialogue> rose from the lodge-children, but the lodge-mother, who was hard of hearing, was for the moment immersed in the preoccupation of her washtub.</p>

  <p>  After an apprehensive glance in the direction of the lodge (the good woman was gifted with the highly militant temper which is sometimes the privilege of deafness) <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character> flew indignantly to the rescue of the struggling captives.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Wilfrid!  Claude!  Let those children go at once.  <character name="Lady Carlotta">Miss Hope</character>, what on earth is the meaning of this scene?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Early Roman history; the Sabine Women, don’t you know?  It’s the Schartz-Metterklume method to make children understand history by acting it themselves; fixes it in their memory, you know.  Of course, if, thanks to your interference, your boys go through life thinking that the Sabine women ultimately escaped, I really cannot be held responsible."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"You may be very clever and modern, <character name="Lady Carlotta">Miss Hope</character>,"</dialogue> said <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character> firmly, <dialogue>"but I should like you to leave here by the next train.  Your luggage will be sent after you as soon as it arrives."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I’m not certain exactly where I shall be for the next few days,"</dialogue> said the dismissed instructress of youth; <dialogue>"you might keep my luggage till I wire my address.  There are only a couple of trunks and some golf-clubs and a leopard cub."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"A leopard cub!"</dialogue> gasped <character name="Mrs. Quabarl">Mrs. Quabarl</character>.  Even in her departure this extraordinary person seemed destined to leave a trail of embarrassment behind her.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Well, it’s rather left off being a cub; it’s more than half-grown, you know.  A fowl every day and a rabbit on Sundays is what it usually gets.  Raw beef makes it too excitable.  Don’t trouble about getting the car for me, I’m rather inclined for a walk."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  And <character name="Lady Carlotta">Lady Carlotta</character> strode out of the Quabarl horizon.</p>

  <p>  The advent of the genuine <character name="Lady Carlotta">Miss Hope</character>, who had made a mistake as to the day on which she was due to arrive, caused a turmoil which that good lady was quite unused to inspiring.  Obviously the Quabarl family had been woefully befooled, but a certain amount of relief came with the knowledge.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"How tiresome for you, dear <character name="Lady Carlotta">Carlotta</character>,"</dialogue> said her hostess, when the overdue guest ultimately arrived; <dialogue>"how very tiresome losing your train and having to stop overnight in a strange place."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Oh dear, no,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Carlotta">Lady Carlotta</character>; <dialogue>"not at all tiresome—for me."</dialogue></p>

  <title>THE SEVENTH PULLET</title>
  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s not the daily grind that I complain of,"</dialogue> said <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> resentfully; <dialogue>"it’s the dull grey sameness of my life outside of office hours.  Nothing of interest comes my way, nothing remarkable or out of the common.  Even the little things that I do try to find some interest in don’t seem to interest other people.  Things in my garden, for instance."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The potato that weighed just over two pounds,"</dialogue> said his friend <character name="Gorworth">Gorworth</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Did I tell you about that?"</dialogue> said <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>; <dialogue>"I was telling the others in the train this morning.  I forgot if I’d told you."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"To be exact you told me that it weighed just under two pounds, but I took into account the fact that abnormal vegetables and freshwater fish have an after-life, in which growth is not arrested."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"You’re just like the others,"</dialogue> said <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> sadly, <dialogue>"you only make fun of it."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The fault is with the potato, not with us,"</dialogue> said <character name="Gorworth">Gorworth</character>; <dialogue>"we are not in the least interested in it because it is not in the least interesting.  The men you go up in the train with every day are just in the same case as yourself; their lives are commonplace and not very interesting to themselves, and they certainly are not going to wax enthusiastic over the commonplace events in other men’s lives.  Tell them something startling, dramatic, piquant that has happened to yourself or to someone in your family, and you will capture their interest at once.  They will talk about you with a certain personal pride to all their acquaintances.  ‘Man I know intimately, fellow called <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>, lives down my way, had two of his fingers clawed clean off by a lobster he was carrying home to supper.  Doctor says entire hand may have to come off.’  Now that is conversation of a very high order.  But imagine walking into a tennis club with the remark: ‘I know a man who has grown a potato weighing two and a quarter pounds.’"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But hang it all, my dear fellow,"</dialogue> said <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> impatiently, <dialogue>"haven’t I just told you that nothing of a remarkable nature ever happens to me?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Invent something,"</dialogue> said <character name="Gorworth">Gorworth</character>.  Since winning a prize for excellence in Scriptural knowledge at a preparatory school he had felt licensed to be a little more unscrupulous than the circle he moved in.  Much might surely be excused to one who in early life could give a list of seventeen trees mentioned in the Old Testament.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"What sort of thing?"</dialogue> asked <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>, somewhat snappishly.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"A snake got into your hen-run yesterday morning and killed six out of seven pullets, first mesmerising them with its eyes and then biting them as they stood helpless.  The seventh pullet was one of that French sort, with feathers all over its eyes, so it escaped the mesmeric snare, and just flew at what it could see of the snake and pecked it to pieces."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Thank you,"</dialogue> said <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> stiffly; <dialogue>"it’s a very clever invention.  If such a thing had really happened in my poultry-run I admit I should have been proud and interested to tell people about it.  But I’d rather stick to fact, even if it is plain fact."</dialogue>  All the same his mind dwelt wistfully on the story of the Seventh Pullet.  He could picture himself telling it in the train amid the absorbed interest of his fellow-passengers.  Unconsciously all sorts of little details and improvements began to suggest themselves.</p>

  <p>  Wistfulness was still his dominant mood when he took his seat in the railway carriage the next morning.  Opposite him sat Stevenham, who had attained to a recognised brevet of importance through the fact of an uncle having dropped dead in the act of voting at a Parliamentary election.  That had happened three years ago, but Stevenham was still deferred to on all questions of home and foreign politics.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Hullo, how’s the giant mushroom, or whatever it was?"</dialogue> was all the notice <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> got from his fellow travellers.</p>

  <p>  Young Duckby, whom he mildly disliked, speedily monopolised the general attention by an account of a domestic bereavement.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Had four young pigeons carried off last night by a whacking big rat.  Oh, a monster he must have been; you could tell by the size of the hole he made breaking into the loft."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  No moderate-sized rat ever seemed to carry out any predatory operations in these regions; they were all enormous in their enormity.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Pretty hard lines that,"</dialogue> continued Duckby, seeing that he had secured the attention and respect of the company; <dialogue>"four squeakers carried off at one swoop.  You’d find it rather hard to match that in the way of unlooked-for bad luck."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I had six pullets out of a pen of seven killed by a snake yesterday afternoon,"</dialogue> said <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>, in a voice which he hardly recognised as his own.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"By a snake?"</dialogue> came in excited chorus.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It fascinated them with its deadly, glittering eyes, one after the other, and struck them down while they stood helpless.  A bedridden neighbour, who wasn’t able to call for assistance, witnessed it all from her bedroom window."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Well, I never!"</dialogue> broke in the chorus, with variations.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The interesting part of it is about the seventh pullet, the one that didn’t get killed,"</dialogue> resumed <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>, slowly lighting a cigarette.  His diffidence had left him, and he was beginning to realise how safe and easy depravity can seem once one has the courage to begin.  <dialogue>"The six dead birds were Minorcas; the seventh was a Houdan with a mop of feathers all over its eyes.  It could hardly see the snake at all, so of course it wasn’t mesmerised like the others.  It just could see something wriggling on the ground, and went for it and pecked it to death."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Well, I’m blessed!"</dialogue> exclaimed the chorus.</p>

  <p>  In the course of the next few days <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> discovered how little the loss of one’s self-respect affects one when one has gained the esteem of the world.  His story found its way into one of the poultry papers, and was copied thence into a daily news-sheet as a matter of general interest.  A lady wrote from the North of Scotland recounting a similar episode which she had witnessed as occurring between a stoat and a blind grouse.  Somehow a lie seems so much less reprehensible when one can call it a lee.</p>

  <p>  For awhile the adapter of the Seventh Pullet story enjoyed to the full his altered standing as a person of consequence, one who had had some share in the strange events of his times.  Then he was thrust once again into the cold grey background by the sudden blossoming into importance of Smith-Paddon, a daily fellow-traveller, whose little girl had been knocked down and nearly hurt by a car belonging to a musical-comedy actress.  The actress was not in the car at the time, but she was in numerous photographs which appeared in the illustrated papers of Zoto Dobreen inquiring after the well-being of Maisie, daughter of Edmund Smith-Paddon, Esq.  With this new human interest to absorb them the travelling companions were almost rude when <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> tried to explain his contrivance for keeping vipers and peregrine falcons out of his chicken-run.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Gorworth">Gorworth</character>, to whom he unburdened himself in private, gave him the same counsel as heretofore.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Invent something."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Yes, but what?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The ready affirmative coupled with the question betrayed a significant shifting of the ethical standpoint.</p>

  <p>  It was a few days later that <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> revealed a chapter of family history to the customary gathering in the railway carriage.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Curious thing happened to my aunt, the one who lives in Paris,"</dialogue> he began.  He had several aunts, but they were all geographically distributed over Greater London.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"She was sitting on a seat in the Bois the other afternoon, after lunching at the Roumanian Legation."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  Whatever the story gained in picturesqueness from the dragging-in of diplomatic <dialogue>"atmosphere,"</dialogue> it ceased from that moment to command any acceptance as a record of current events.  <character name="Gorworth">Gorworth</character> had warned his neophyte that this would be the case, but the traditional enthusiasm of the neophyte had triumphed over discretion.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"She was feeling rather drowsy, the effect probably of the champagne, which she’s not in the habit of taking in the middle of the day."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  A subdued murmur of admiration went round the company.  <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>’s aunts were not used to taking champagne in the middle of the year, regarding it exclusively as a Christmas and New Year accessory.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Presently a rather portly gentleman passed by her seat and paused an instant to light a cigar.  At that moment a youngish man came up behind him, drew the blade from a swordstick, and stabbed him half a dozen times through and through.  ‘Scoundrel,’ he cried to his victim, ‘you do not know me.  My name is Henri Leturc.’  The elder man wiped away some of the blood that was spattering his clothes, turned to his assailant, and said: ‘And since when has an attempted assassination been considered an introduction?’  Then he finished lighting his cigar and walked away.  My aunt had intended screaming for the police, but seeing the indifference with which the principal in the affair treated the matter she felt that it would be an impertinence on her part to interfere.  Of course I need hardly say she put the whole thing down to the effects of a warm, drowsy afternoon and the Legation champagne.  Now comes the astonishing part of my story.  A fortnight later a bank manager was stabbed to death with a swordstick in that very part of the Bois.  His assassin was the son of a charwoman formerly working at the bank, who had been dismissed from her job by the manager on account of chronic intemperance.  His name was Henri Leturc."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  From that moment <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> was tacitly accepted as the Munchausen of the party.  No effort was spared to draw him out from day to day in the exercise of testing their powers of credulity, and <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>, in the false security of an assured and receptive audience, waxed industrious and ingenious in supplying the demand for marvels.  Duckby’s satirical story of a tame otter that had a tank in the garden to swim in, and whined restlessly whenever the water-rate was overdue, was scarcely an unfair parody of some of <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>’s wilder efforts.  And then one day came Nemesis.</p>

  <p>  Returning to his villa one evening <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> found his wife sitting in front of a pack of cards, which she was scrutinising with unusual concentration.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The same old patience-game?"</dialogue> he asked carelessly.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"No, dear; this is the Death’s Head patience, the most difficult of them all.  I’ve never got it to work out, and somehow I should be rather frightened if I did.  Mother only got it out once in her life; she was afraid of it, too.  Her great-aunt had done it once and fallen dead from excitement the next moment, and mother always had a feeling that she would die if she ever got it out.  She died the same night that she did it.  She was in bad health at the time, certainly, but it was a strange coincidence."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Don’t do it if it frightens you,"</dialogue> was <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>’s practical comment as he left the room.  A few minutes later his wife called to him.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"John, it gave me such a turn, I nearly got it out.  Only the five of diamonds held me up at the end.  I really thought I’d done it."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Why, you can do it,"</dialogue> said <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>, who had come back to the room; <dialogue>"if you shift the eight of clubs on to that open nine the five can be moved on to the six."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  His wife made the suggested move with hasty, trembling fingers, and piled the outstanding cards on to their respective packs.  Then she followed the example of her mother and great-grand-aunt.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> had been genuinely fond of his wife, but in the midst of his bereavement one dominant thought obtruded itself.  Something sensational and real had at last come into his life; no longer was it a grey, colourless record.  The headlines which might appropriately describe his domestic tragedy kept shaping themselves in his brain.  <dialogue>"Inherited presentiment comes true."</dialogue>  <dialogue>"The Death’s Head patience: Card-game that justified its sinister name in three generations."</dialogue>  He wrote out a full story of the fatal occurrence for the Essex Vedette, the editor of which was a friend of his, and to another friend he gave a condensed account, to be taken up to the office of one of the halfpenny dailies.  But in both cases his reputation as a romancer stood fatally in the way of the fulfilment of his ambitions.  <dialogue>"Not the right thing to be Munchausening in a time of sorrow"</dialogue> agreed his friends among themselves, and a brief note of regret at the <dialogue>"sudden death of the wife of our respected neighbour, Mr. John <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character>, from heart failure,"</dialogue> appearing in the news column of the local paper was the forlorn outcome of his visions of widespread publicity.</p>

  <p>  <character name="Blenkinthrope">Blenkinthrope</character> shrank from the society of his erstwhile travelling companions and took to travelling townwards by an earlier train.  He sometimes tries to enlist the sympathy and attention of a chance acquaintance in details of the whistling prowess of his best canary or the dimensions of his largest beetroot; he scarcely recognises himself as the man who was once spoken about and pointed out as the owner of the Seventh Pullet.</p>

  <title>THE BLIND SPOT</title>
  <p>  <dialogue>"You’ve just come back from <character name="Adelaide">Adelaide</character>’s funeral, haven’t you?"</dialogue> said <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character> to his nephew; <dialogue>"I suppose it was very like most other funerals?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I’ll tell you all about it at lunch,"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"You’ll do nothing of the sort.  It wouldn’t be respectful either to your great-aunt’s memory or to the lunch.  We begin with Spanish olives, then a borshch, then more olives and a bird of some kind, and a rather enticing Rhenish wine, not at all expensive as wines go in this country, but still quite laudable in its way.  Now there’s absolutely nothing in that menu that harmonises in the least with the subject of your great-aunt <character name="Adelaide">Adelaide</character> or her funeral.  She was a charming woman, and quite as intelligent as she had any need to be, but somehow she always reminded me of an English cook’s idea of a Madras curry."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"She used to say you were frivolous,"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>.  Something in his tone suggested that he rather endorsed the verdict.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I believe I once considerably scandalised her by declaring that clear soup was a more important factor in life than a clear conscience.  She had very little sense of proportion.  By the way, she made you her principal heir, didn’t she?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Yes,"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>, <dialogue>"and executor as well.  It’s in that connection that I particularly want to speak to you."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Business is not my strong point at any time,"</dialogue> said <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character>, <dialogue>"and certainly not when we’re on the immediate threshold of lunch."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It isn’t exactly business,"</dialogue> explained <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>, as he followed his uncle into the dining-room.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s something rather serious.  Very serious."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Then we can’t possibly speak about it now,"</dialogue> said <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character>; <dialogue>"no one could talk seriously during a borshch.  A beautifully constructed borshch, such as you are going to experience presently, ought not only to banish conversation but almost to annihilate thought.  Later on, when we arrive at the second stage of olives, I shall be quite ready to discuss that new book on Borrow, or, if you prefer it, the present situation in the Grand Duchy of Luxemburg.  But I absolutely decline to talk anything approaching business till we have finished with the bird."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  For the greater part of the meal <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character> sat in an abstracted silence, the silence of a man whose mind is focussed on one topic.  When the coffee stage had been reached he launched himself suddenly athwart his uncle’s reminiscences of the Court of Luxemburg.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I think I told you that great-aunt <character name="Adelaide">Adelaide</character> had made me her executor.  There wasn’t very much to be done in the way of legal matters, but I had to go through her papers."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"That would be a fairly heavy task in itself.  I should imagine there were reams of family letters."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Stacks of them, and most of them highly uninteresting.  There was one packet, however, which I thought might repay a careful perusal.  It was a bundle of correspondence from her brother <character name="Peter">Peter</character>."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The Canon of tragic memory,"</dialogue> said <character name="Sir Lulworth">Lulworth</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Exactly, of tragic memory, as you say; a tragedy that has never been fathomed."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Probably the simplest explanation was the correct one,"</dialogue> said <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character>; <dialogue>"he slipped on the stone staircase and fractured his skull in falling."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character> shook his head.  <dialogue>"The medical evidence all went to prove that the blow on the head was struck by some one coming up behind him.  A wound caused by violent contact with the steps could not possibly have been inflicted at that angle of the skull.  They experimented with a dummy figure falling in every conceivable position."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But the motive?"</dialogue> exclaimed <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character>; <dialogue>"no one had any interest in doing away with him, and the number of people who destroy Canons of the Established Church for the mere fun of killing must be extremely limited.  Of course there are individuals of weak mental balance who do that sort of thing, but they seldom conceal their handiwork; they are more generally inclined to parade it."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"His cook was under suspicion,"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character> shortly.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I know he was,"</dialogue> said <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character>, <dialogue>"simply because he was about the only person on the premises at the time of the tragedy.  But could anything be sillier than trying to fasten a charge of murder on to Sebastien?  He had nothing to gain, in fact, a good deal to lose, from the death of his employer.  The Canon was paying him quite as good wages as I was able to offer him when I took him over into my service.  I have since raised them to something a little more in accordance with his real worth, but at the time he was glad to find a new place without troubling about an increase of wages.  People were fighting rather shy of him, and he had no friends in this country.  No; if anyone in the world was interested in the prolonged life and unimpaired digestion of the Canon it would certainly be Sebastien."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"People don’t always weigh the consequences of their rash acts,"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>, <dialogue>"otherwise there would be very few murders committed.  Sebastien is a man of hot temper."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"He is a southerner,"</dialogue> admitted <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character>; <dialogue>"to be geographically exact I believe he hails from the French slopes of the Pyrenees.  I took that into consideration when he nearly killed the gardener’s boy the other day for bringing him a spurious substitute for sorrel.  One must always make allowances for origin and locality and early environment; ‘Tell me your longitude and I’ll know what latitude to allow you,’ is my motto."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"There, you see,"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>, <dialogue>"he nearly killed the gardener’s boy."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"My dear <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>, between nearly killing a gardener’s boy and altogether killing a Canon there is a wide difference.  No doubt you have often felt a temporary desire to kill a gardener’s boy; you have never given way to it, and I respect you for your self-control.  But I don’t suppose you have ever wanted to kill an octogenarian Canon.  Besides, as far as we know, there had never been any quarrel or disagreement between the two men.  The evidence at the inquest brought that out very clearly."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Ah!"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>, with the air of a man coming at last into a deferred inheritance of conversational importance, <dialogue>"that is precisely what I want to speak to you about."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  He pushed away his coffee cup and drew a pocket-book from his inner breast-pocket.  From the depths of the pocket-book he produced an envelope, and from the envelope he extracted a letter, closely written in a small, neat handwriting.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"One of the Canon’s numerous letters to Aunt <character name="Adelaide">Adelaide</character>,"</dialogue> he explained, <dialogue>"written a few days before his death.  Her memory was already failing when she received it, and I daresay she forgot the contents as soon as she had read it; otherwise, in the light of what subsequently happened, we should have heard something of this letter before now.  If it had been produced at the inquest I fancy it would have made some difference in the course of affairs.  The evidence, as you remarked just now, choked off suspicion against Sebastien by disclosing an utter absence of anything that could be considered a motive or provocation for the crime, if crime there was."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Oh, read the letter,"</dialogue> said <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character> impatiently.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s a long rambling affair, like most of his letters in his later years,"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>.  <dialogue>"I’ll read the part that bears immediately on the mystery.</p>

  <p>  “‘I very much fear I shall have to get rid of <character name="Sebastien">Sebastien</character>.  He cooks divinely, but he has the temper of a fiend or an anthropoid ape, and I am really in bodily fear of him.  We had a dispute the other day as to the correct sort of lunch to be served on Ash Wednesday, and I got so irritated and annoyed at his conceit and obstinacy that at last I threw a cupful of coffee in his face and called him at the same time an impudent jackanapes.  Very little of the coffee went actually in his face, but I have never seen a human being show such deplorable lack of self-control.  I laughed at the threat of killing me that he spluttered out in his rage, and thought the whole thing would blow over, but I have several times since caught him scowling and muttering in a highly unpleasant fashion, and lately I have fancied that he was dogging my footsteps about the grounds, particularly when I walk of an evening in the Italian Garden.’</p>

  <p>  “It was on the steps in the Italian Garden that the body was found,"</dialogue> commented <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>, and resumed reading.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"‘I daresay the danger is imaginary; but I shall feel more at ease when he has quitted my service.’"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character> paused for a moment at the conclusion of the extract; then, as his uncle made no remark, he added: <dialogue>"If lack of motive was the only factor that saved Sebastien from prosecution I fancy this letter will put a different complexion on matters."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Have you shown it to anyone else?"</dialogue> asked <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character>, reaching out his hand for the incriminating piece of paper.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"No,"</dialogue> said <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>, handing it across the table, <dialogue>"I thought I would tell you about it first.  Heavens, what are you doing?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>’s voice rose almost to a scream.  <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character> had flung the paper well and truly into the glowing centre of the grate.  The small, neat handwriting shrivelled into black flaky nothingness.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"What on earth did you do that for?"</dialogue> gasped <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>.  <dialogue>"That letter was our one piece of evidence to connect Sebastien with the crime."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"That is why I destroyed it,"</dialogue> said <character name="Sir Lulworth">Sir Lulworth</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But why should you want to shield him?"</dialogue> cried <character name="Egbert">Egbert</character>; <dialogue>"the man is a common murderer."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"A common murderer, possibly, but a very uncommon cook."</dialogue></p>

  <title>DUSK</title>
  <p>  <character name="Norman Gortsby">Norman Gortsby</character> sat on a bench in the Park, with his back to a strip of bush-planted sward, fenced by the park railings, and the Row fronting him across a wide stretch of carriage drive.  Hyde Park Corner, with its rattle and hoot of traffic, lay immediately to his right.  It was some thirty minutes past six on an early March evening, and dusk had fallen heavily over the scene, dusk mitigated by some faint moonlight and many street lamps.  There was a wide emptiness over road and sidewalk, and yet there were many unconsidered figures moving silently through the half-light, or dotted unobtrusively on bench and chair, scarcely to be distinguished from the shadowed gloom in which they sat.</p>

  <p>  The scene pleased <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> and harmonised with his present mood.  Dusk, to his mind, was the hour of the defeated.  Men and women, who had fought and lost, who hid their fallen fortunes and dead hopes as far as possible from the scrutiny of the curious, came forth in this hour of gloaming, when their shabby clothes and bowed shoulders and unhappy eyes might pass unnoticed, or, at any rate, unrecognised.</p>

  <p>  A king that is conquered must see strange looks,</p>
  <p>  So bitter a thing is the heart of man.</p>

  <p>  The wanderers in the dusk did not choose to have strange looks fasten on them, therefore they came out in this bat-fashion, taking their pleasure sadly in a pleasure-ground that had emptied of its rightful occupants.  Beyond the sheltering screen of bushes and palings came a realm of brilliant lights and noisy, rushing traffic.  A blazing, many-tiered stretch of windows shone through the dusk and almost dispersed it, marking the haunts of those other people, who held their own in life’s struggle, or at any rate had not had to admit failure.  So <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character>’s imagination pictured things as he sat on his bench in the almost deserted walk.  He was in the mood to count himself among the defeated.  Money troubles did not press on him; had he so wished he could have strolled into the thoroughfares of light and noise, and taken his place among the jostling ranks of those who enjoyed prosperity or struggled for it.  He had failed in a more subtle ambition, and for the moment he was heartsore and disillusionised, and not disinclined to take a certain cynical pleasure in observing and labelling his fellow wanderers as they went their ways in the dark stretches between the lamp-lights.</p>

  <p>  On the bench by his side sat an elderly gentleman with a drooping air of defiance that was probably the remaining vestige of self-respect in an individual who had ceased to defy successfully anybody or anything.  His clothes could scarcely be called shabby, at least they passed muster in the half-light, but one’s imagination could not have pictured the wearer embarking on the purchase of a half-crown box of chocolates or laying out ninepence on a carnation buttonhole.  He belonged unmistakably to that forlorn orchestra to whose piping no one dances; he was one of the world’s lamenters who induce no responsive weeping.  As he rose to go <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> imagined him returning to a home circle where he was snubbed and of no account, or to some bleak lodging where his ability to pay a weekly bill was the beginning and end of the interest he inspired.  His retreating figure vanished slowly into the shadows, and his place on the bench was taken almost immediately by a young man, fairly well dressed but scarcely more cheerful of mien than his predecessor.  As if to emphasise the fact that the world went badly with him the new-corner unburdened himself of an angry and very audible expletive as he flung himself into the seat.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"You don’t seem in a very good temper,"</dialogue> said <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character>, judging that he was expected to take due notice of the demonstration.</p>

  <p>  The young man turned to him with a look of disarming frankness which put him instantly on his guard.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"You wouldn’t be in a good temper if you were in the fix I’m in,"</dialogue> he said; <dialogue>"I’ve done the silliest thing I’ve ever done in my life."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Yes?"</dialogue> said <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> dispassionately.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Came up this afternoon, meaning to stay at the Patagonian Hotel in Berkshire Square,"</dialogue> continued the young man; <dialogue>"when I got there I found it had been pulled down some weeks ago and a cinema theatre run up on the site.  The taxi driver recommended me to another hotel some way off and I went there.  I just sent a letter to my people, giving them the address, and then I went out to buy some soap—I’d forgotten to pack any and I hate using hotel soap.  Then I strolled about a bit, had a drink at a bar and looked at the shops, and when I came to turn my steps back to the hotel I suddenly realised that I didn’t remember its name or even what street it was in.  There’s a nice predicament for a fellow who hasn’t any friends or connections in London!  Of course I can wire to my people for the address, but they won’t have got my letter till to-morrow; meantime I’m without any money, came out with about a shilling on me, which went in buying the soap and getting the drink, and here I am, wandering about with twopence in my pocket and nowhere to go for the night."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  There was an eloquent pause after the story had been told.  <dialogue>"I suppose you think I’ve spun you rather an impossible yarn,"</dialogue> said the young man presently, with a suggestion of resentment in his voice.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Not at all impossible,"</dialogue> said <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> judicially; <dialogue>"I remember doing exactly the same thing once in a foreign capital, and on that occasion there were two of us, which made it more remarkable.  Luckily we remembered that the hotel was on a sort of canal, and when we struck the canal we were able to find our way back to the hotel."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The youth brightened at the reminiscence.  <dialogue>"In a foreign city I wouldn’t mind so much,"</dialogue> he said; <dialogue>"one could go to one’s Consul and get the requisite help from him.  Here in one’s own land one is far more derelict if one gets into a fix.  Unless I can find some decent chap to swallow my story and lend me some money I seem likely to spend the night on the Embankment.  I’m glad, anyhow, that you don’t think the story outrageously improbable."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  He threw a good deal of warmth into the last remark, as though perhaps to indicate his hope that <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> did not fall far short of the requisite decency.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Of course,"</dialogue> said <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> slowly, <dialogue>"the weak point of your story is that you can’t produce the soap."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The young man sat forward hurriedly, felt rapidly in the pockets of his overcoat, and then jumped to his feet.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I must have lost it,"</dialogue> he muttered angrily.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"To lose an hotel and a cake of soap on one afternoon suggests wilful carelessness,"</dialogue> said <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character>, but the young man scarcely waited to hear the end of the remark.  He flitted away down the path, his head held high, with an air of somewhat jaded jauntiness.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It was a pity,"</dialogue> mused <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character>; <dialogue>"the going out to get one’s own soap was the one convincing touch in the whole story, and yet it was just that little detail that brought him to grief.  If he had had the brilliant forethought to provide himself with a cake of soap, wrapped and sealed with all the solicitude of the chemist’s counter, he would have been a genius in his particular line.  In his particular line genius certainly consists of an infinite capacity for taking precautions."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  With that reflection <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> rose to go; as he did so an exclamation of concern escaped him.  Lying on the ground by the side of the bench was a small oval packet, wrapped and sealed with the solicitude of a chemist’s counter.  It could be nothing else but a cake of soap, and it had evidently fallen out of the youth’s overcoat pocket when he flung himself down on the seat.  In another moment <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> was scudding along the dusk-shrouded path in anxious quest for a youthful figure in a light overcoat.  He had nearly given up the search when he caught sight of the object of his pursuit standing irresolutely on the border of the carriage drive, evidently uncertain whether to strike across the Park or make for the bustling pavements of Knightsbridge.  He turned round sharply with an air of defensive hostility when he found <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> hailing him.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"The important witness to the genuineness of your story has turned up,"</dialogue> said <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character>, holding out the cake of soap; <dialogue>"it must have slid out of your overcoat pocket when you sat down on the seat.  I saw it on the ground after you left.  You must excuse my disbelief, but appearances were really rather against you, and now, as I appealed to the testimony of the soap I think I ought to abide by its verdict.  If the loan of a sovereign is any good to you—"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The young man hastily removed all doubt on the subject by pocketing the coin.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Here is my card with my address,"</dialogue> continued <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character>; <dialogue>"any day this week will do for returning the money, and here is the soap—don’t lose it again it’s been a good friend to you."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Lucky thing your finding it,"</dialogue> said the youth, and then, with a catch in his voice, he blurted out a word or two of thanks and fled headlong in the direction of Knightsbridge.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Poor boy, he as nearly as possible broke down,"</dialogue> said <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> to himself.  <dialogue>"I don’t wonder either; the relief from his quandary must have been acute.  It’s a lesson to me not to be too clever in judging by circumstances."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  As <character name="Norman Gortsby">Gortsby</character> retraced his steps past the seat where the little drama had taken place he saw an elderly gentleman poking and peering beneath it and on all sides of it, and recognised his earlier fellow occupant.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Have you lost anything, sir?"</dialogue> he asked.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Yes, sir, a cake of soap."</dialogue></p>

  <title> A TOUCH OF REALISM</title>
  <p>  <dialogue>"I hope you’ve come full of suggestions for Christmas,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character> to her latest arrived guest; <dialogue>"the old-fashioned Christmas and the up-to-date Christmas are both so played out.  I want to have something really original this year."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I was staying with the Mathesons last month,"</dialogue> said Blanche Boveal eagerly, <dialogue>"and we had such a good idea.  Every one in the house-party had to be a character and behave consistently all the time, and at the end of the visit one had to guess what every one’s character was.  The one who was voted to have acted his or her character best got a prize."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It sounds amusing,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I was St. Francis of Assisi,"</dialogue> continued Blanche; <dialogue>"we hadn’t got to keep to our right sexes.  I kept getting up in the middle of a meal, and throwing out food to the birds; you see, the chief thing that one remembers of St. Francis is that he was fond of the birds.  Every one was so stupid about it, and thought that I was the old man who feeds the sparrows in the Tuileries Gardens.  Then <character name="Colonel Pentley">Colonel Pentley</character> was the Jolly Miller on the banks of Dee."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"How on earth did he do that?"</dialogue> asked <character name="Bertie van Tahn">Bertie van Tahn</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"‘He laughed and sang from morn till night,’"</dialogue> explained Blanche.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"How dreadful for the rest of you,"</dialogue> said Bertie; <dialogue>"and anyway he wasn’t on the banks of Dee."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"One had to imagine that,"</dialogue> said Blanche.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"If you could imagine all that you might as well imagine cattle on the further bank and keep on calling them home, Mary-fashion, across the sands of Dee.  Or you might change the river to the Yarrow and imagine it was on the top of you, and say you were Willie, or whoever it was, drowned in Yarrow."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Of course it’s easy to make fun of it,"</dialogue> said Blanche sharply, <dialogue>"but it was extremely interesting and amusing.  The prize was rather a fiasco, though.  You see, Millie Matheson said her character was Lady Bountiful, and as she was our hostess of course we all had to vote that she had carried out her character better than anyone.  Otherwise I ought to have got the prize."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s quite an idea for a Christmas party,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character>; <dialogue>"we must certainly do it here."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  Sir Nicholas was not so enthusiastic.  <dialogue>"Are you quite sure, my dear, that you’re wise in doing this thing?"</dialogue> he said to his wife when they were alone together.  <dialogue>"It might do very well at the Mathesons, where they had rather a staid, elderly house-party, but here it will be a different matter.  There is the Durmot flapper, for instance, who simply stops at nothing, and you know what Van Tahn is like.  Then there is Cyril <character name="Skatterly">Skatterly</character>; he has madness on one side of his family and a Hungarian grandmother on the other."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I don’t see what they could do that would matter,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s the unknown that is to be dreaded,"</dialogue> said Sir Nicholas.  <dialogue>"If <character name="Skatterly">Skatterly</character> took it into his head to represent a Bull of Bashan, well, I’d rather not be here."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Of course we shan’t allow any Bible characters.  Besides, I don’t know what the Bulls of Bashan really did that was so very dreadful; they just came round and gaped, as far as I remember."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"My dear, you don’t know what <character name="Skatterly">Skatterly</character>’s Hungarian imagination mightn’t read into the part; it would be small satisfaction to say to him afterwards: ‘You’ve behaved as no Bull of Bashan would have behaved.’"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Oh, you’re an alarmist,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character>; <dialogue>"I particularly want to have this idea carried out.  It will be sure to be talked about a lot."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"That is quite possible,"</dialogue> said Sir Nicholas.</p>

  <p>  * * * * *</p>

  <p>  Dinner that evening was not a particularly lively affair; the strain of trying to impersonate a self-imposed character or to glean hints of identity from other people’s conduct acted as a check on the natural festivity of such a gathering.  There was a general feeling of gratitude and acquiescence when good-natured Rachel Klammerstein suggested that there should be an hour or two’s respite from <dialogue>"the game"</dialogue> while they all listened to a little piano-playing after dinner.  Rachel’s love of piano music was not indiscriminate, and concentrated itself chiefly on selections rendered by her idolised offspring, Moritz and Augusta, who, to do them justice, played remarkably well.</p>

  <p>  The Klammersteins were deservedly popular as Christmas guests; they gave expensive gifts lavishly on Christmas Day and New Year, and Mrs. Klammerstein had already dropped hints of her intention to present the prize for the best enacted character in the game competition.  Every one had brightened at this prospect; if it had fallen to <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character>, as hostess, to provide the prize, she would have considered that a little souvenir of some twenty or twenty-five shillings’ value would meet the case, whereas coming from a Klammerstein source it would certainly run to several guineas.</p>

  <p>  The close time for impersonation efforts came to an end with the final withdrawal of Moritz and Augusta from the piano.  Blanche Boveal retired early, leaving the room in a series of laboured leaps that she hoped might be recognised as a tolerable imitation of Pavlova.  <character name="Vera">Vera</character> Durmot, the sixteen-year-old flapper, expressed her confident opinion that the performance was intended to typify Mark Twain’s famous jumping frog, and her diagnosis of the case found general acceptance.  Another guest to set an example of early bed-going was <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character> Plubley, who conducted his life on a minutely regulated system of time-tables and hygienic routine.  <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character> was a plump, indolent young man of seven-and-twenty, whose mother had early in his life decided for him that he was unusually delicate, and by dint of much coddling and home-keeping had succeeded in making him physically soft and mentally peevish.  Nine hours’ unbroken sleep, preceded by elaborate breathing exercises and other hygienic ritual, was among the indispensable regulations which <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character> imposed on himself, and there were innumerable small observances which he exacted from those who were in any way obliged to minister to his requirements; a special teapot for the decoction of his early tea was always solemnly handed over to the bedroom staff of any house in which he happened to be staying.  No one had ever quite mastered the mechanism of this precious vessel, but <character name="Bertie van Tahn">Bertie van Tahn</character> was responsible for the legend that its spout had to be kept facing north during the process of infusion.</p>

  <p>  On this particular night the irreducible nine hours were severely mutilated by the sudden and by no means noiseless incursion of a pyjama-clad figure into <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character>’s room at an hour midway between midnight and dawn.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"What is the matter?  What are you looking for?"</dialogue> asked the awakened and astonished <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character>, slowly recognising Van Tahn, who appeared to be searching hastily for something he had lost.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Looking for sheep,"</dialogue> was the reply.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Sheep?"</dialogue> exclaimed <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Yes, sheep.  You don’t suppose I’m looking for giraffes, do you?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I don’t see why you should expect to find either in my room,"</dialogue> retorted <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character> furiously.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I can’t argue the matter at this hour of the night,"</dialogue> said Bertie, and began hastily rummaging in the chest of drawers.  Shirts and underwear went flying on to the floor.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"There are no sheep here, I tell you,"</dialogue> screamed <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I’ve only got your word for it,"</dialogue> said Bertie, whisking most of the bedclothes on to the floor; <dialogue>"if you weren’t concealing something you wouldn’t be so agitated."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character> was by this time convinced that Van Tahn was raving mad, and made an anxious effort to humour him.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Go back to bed like a dear fellow,"</dialogue> he pleaded, <dialogue>"and your sheep will turn up all right in the morning."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I daresay,"</dialogue> said Bertie gloomily, <dialogue>"without their tails.  Nice fool I shall look with a lot of Manx sheep."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  And by way of emphasising his annoyance at the prospect he sent <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character>’s pillows flying to the top of the wardrobe.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But why no tails?"</dialogue> asked <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character>, whose teeth were chattering with fear and rage and lowered temperature.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"My dear boy, have you never heard the ballad of Little Bo-Peep?"</dialogue> said Bertie with a chuckle.  <dialogue>"It’s my character in the Game, you know.  If I didn’t go hunting about for my lost sheep no one would be able to guess who I was; and now go to sleepy weeps like a good child or I shall be cross with you."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I leave you to imagine,"</dialogue> wrote <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character> in the course of a long letter to his mother, <dialogue>"how much sleep I was able to recover that night, and you know how essential nine uninterrupted hours of slumber are to my health."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  On the other hand he was able to devote some wakeful hours to exercises in breathing wrath and fury against <character name="Bertie van Tahn">Bertie van Tahn</character>.</p>

  <p>  Breakfast at Blonzecourt was a scattered meal, on the <dialogue>"come when you please"</dialogue> principle, but the house-party was supposed to gather in full strength at lunch.  On the day after the <dialogue>"Game"</dialogue> had been started there were, however, some notable absentees.  <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character> Plubley, for instance, was reported to be nursing a headache.  A large breakfast and an <dialogue>"A.B.C."</dialogue> had been taken up to his room, but he had made no appearance in the flesh.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I expect he’s playing up to some character,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character> Durmot; <dialogue>"isn’t there a thing of Molière’s, ‘Le Malade Imaginaire’?  I expect he’s that."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  Eight or nine lists came out, and were duly pencilled with the suggestion.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"And where are the Klammersteins?"</dialogue> asked <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character>; <dialogue>"they’re usually so punctual."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Another character pose, perhaps,"</dialogue> said <character name="Bertie van Tahn">Bertie van Tahn</character>; <dialogue>"‘the Lost Ten Tribes.’"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But there are only three of them.  Besides, they’ll want their lunch.  Hasn’t anyone seen anything of them?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Didn’t you take them out in your car?"</dialogue> asked Blanche Boveal, addressing herself to Cyril <character name="Skatterly">Skatterly</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Yes, took them out to Slogberry Moor immediately after breakfast.  Miss Durmot came too."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I saw you and <character name="Vera">Vera</character> come back,"</dialogue> said <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character>, <dialogue>"but I didn’t see the Klammersteins.  Did you put them down in the village?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"No,"</dialogue> said <character name="Skatterly">Skatterly</character> shortly.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But where are they?  Where did you leave them?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"We left them on Slogberry Moor,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character> calmly.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"On Slogberry Moor?  Why, it’s more than thirty miles away!  How are they going to get back?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"We didn’t stop to consider that,"</dialogue> said <character name="Skatterly">Skatterly</character>; <dialogue>"we asked them to get out for a moment, on the pretence that the car had stuck, and then we dashed off full speed and left them there."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But how dare you do such a thing?  It’s most inhuman!  Why, it’s been snowing for the last hour."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I expect there’ll be a cottage or farmhouse somewhere if they walk a mile or two."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"But why on earth have you done it?"</dialogue></p>

  <p>  The question came in a chorus of indignant bewilderment.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"That would be telling what our characters are meant to be,"</dialogue> said <character name="Vera">Vera</character>.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"Didn’t I warn you?"</dialogue> said Sir Nicholas tragically to his wife.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"It’s something to do with Spanish history; we don’t mind giving you that clue,"</dialogue> said <character name="Skatterly">Skatterly</character>, helping himself cheerfully to salad, and then <character name="Bertie van Tahn">Bertie van Tahn</character> broke forth into peals of joyous laughter.</p>

  <p>  <dialogue>"I’ve got it!  <character name="Ferdinand">Ferdinand</character> and <character name="Isabella"Isabella</character> deporting the Jews!  Oh, lovely!  Those two have certainly won the prize; we shan’t get anything to beat that for thoroughness."</dialogue></p>

  <p>  <character name="Lady Blonze">Lady Blonze</character>’s Christmas party was talked about and written about to an extent that she had not anticipated in her most ambitious moments.  The letters from <character name="Waldo">Waldo</character>’s mother would alone have made it memorable.</p>
</text>
</xml>













<title> to show the title of the story. I marked this so there is a clear separation between when a story starts and another begins
<p> to show when a new paragraph/line starts. I marked this so there's more clarity when reading
 <character> used to mark any time a character is introduced or mentioned. I marked characters so I could keep track of who's important and how they act.
<dialogue> To mark when characters are speaking. I marked dialogue to separate what people are saying from the rest of the story.
There are also times I tagged specific nouns like locations and landforms so the reader can understand what is happening.


Marking up my text was a long and tiring process that took way more effort than I expected. At first, I thought I could just fly through it, but once I actually got started, I realized how much thinking it required. I had to slow down and look closely at every part of the story, which forced me to read way more carefully than I did the first time. That alone helped me understand the text on a deeper level.

I chose to mark up dialogue, character names, and moments that felt particularly important to understanding the story. I picked these elements because they show what makes H. H. Munro's (aka Saki) stories so unique. The way he uses dry humor and strange situations to make fun of society. As I tagged these parts, I began to see patterns I hadn’t noticed before. For example, Saki often builds up a situation with calm, normal language, and then throws in something really morbid or ridiculous at the end, which gives it that sharp, ironic twist. I wouldn’t have picked up on how often he does that if I hadn’t been noticing those exact moments.

More specifically, I learned that Saki’s humor is very intentional and layered. It’s not just “funny old stories” — it’s carefully crafted satire that still feels relevant today. By noticing selfish behavior, lies, or misunderstandings, I saw how those ideas kept showing up again and again. Even though the characters are exaggerated, their actions reflect real human flaws, which is probably why the humor still lands.

Overall, the markup helped me understand how Saki uses structure, tone, and timing to deliver his humor, and how all of it is tied to a deeper critique of people and society.
